Guide to the Cornell Outing Club records, 1941-2012.
Cornell Outing Club records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Outing Club records, 1941-2012.
37-6-3416
Cornell Outing Club.
5.3 cubic ft.
Financial documents, photographs, printed materials, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documentation of all Outing Club activities between 1930 and 2012, and maps of the surrounding areas. Meeting minutes, financial statements, membership lists, and other items documenting the clubs activities are included.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In the 1950s college outing clubs in the northeast associated in the Intercollegiate Outing Clubs Association (IOCA) which sponsored numerous events. In 1952 a Finger Lakes Regional IOCA was established for local colleges and universities.The Cornell Outing Club has been an active part of Cornell life since the 1920s.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Newsletters from the Cornell Outing Club and the Finger Lakes Regional club; "The Outing Club Handbook"; and photographs, with some identification, from the Cornell Outing Club and the Intercollegiate Outing Club Annual Conference in 1952, collected by Hugh E. Kingery '54. This collection includes photos, trip history, budget history, and newsletters. Documentation of all Outing Club activities between 1930 and 2012, and maps of the surrounding areas. Meeting minutes, financial statements, membership lists, and other items documenting the clubs activities are included. Many photographs of events on Beebe Lake and on trips are included, camping, caving, ice climbing, Japes Lodge, etc..
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Outing Club.; Kingery, Hugh E.; Finger Lakes Regional Intercollegiate Outing Clubs Association.; Intercollegiate Outing Clubs Association
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Trips that were, gear accounted for (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Budget, 2003-04 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 2000-01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 2001-02 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- COC bank information (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Gear signout sheets, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Memberships and bank statements, 2003-08 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- COC budget, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- IOCA newsletter, 1963-68 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Treasurer's reports, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- IOCA bulletin, 1955-63 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- IOCA newsletter, 1968-74 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- IOCA, 1967-70 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- IOCA newsletter, 1970-82 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Rope logs (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Transactions, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Trips back, gear's not (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 2002-03 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Safety and liability forms, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "Climbing in Ithaca", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- COC bank transactions (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Airin' our views, 1971-81 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Airin' our views, 1965-71 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Airin' our views, 1974-81 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Airin' our views, 1965-75 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Rock climbing, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Outing Club Handbook, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- IOCA newsletter, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Newsletter, Air'n Our Views, 1951-1954, 1970's (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Past checking account info, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Adirondacks and northern New York, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Daily Sun: Closing of Japes, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Trip Reports, 1980's (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "A One Track Trip for a One Track Mind" Alfred Davidson, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- List of COC Presidents, 1938-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Information and minutes, 1990's (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Info and minutes, 1970's (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Info and minutes, 1940's (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Info and minutes, 1960's (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Info and minutes, 1980's (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Trip Reports, 1970's (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Trails of New England and surrounding areas, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- "The Scrawl", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Election of Officers form (Box 2, Folder 16)
- COC Insurance Policies, 1969-78 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Outdoor Center, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Care of Equipment, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Rental Agreements of Various Outing Clubs, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Kayak Maintenance and Repair, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- American Kayaking Association and other organizations, 1960-80 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Old equipment inventories and rental rates, 1974-76 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Equipment used by members, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Anything Floats, 1984-90 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Float Trip Permits, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- COC Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Cayuga Trails, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Backpacking in Pennsylvania, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Skiing Manuals and Trails, 1968-70 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Rock Climbing, 1980-81 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Australian Alpine Club, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Ice Climbing, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Publicity Info, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Non-poster originals forms, masters, 1990-91 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Banner, 1987-90 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Weekly meeting info, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Miscellaneous photos (Box 2, Folder 38)
  Includes IOCA Annual Conference 1952.
- Winter mountaineering reports, 1948-49 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Trips, 1983-86 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Schedules, Brochures, Trip costs, 1950's (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Reported Activities, 1992-97 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Trip reports, 2001-02 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Trip reports, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Minutes, reports, and meetings, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- COC meeting minutes, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Trips, 1982-94 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Trip reports, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- COC membership list, 2002-03 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Reel Rock DVD, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- COC meeting minutes, 2003-04 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Meeting minutes, 2000-01 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Report on COC conference, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- IOCA conference report, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- COC SAFC Financial aid history, 1992-97 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- COC Statements, 1993-2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Expenditure sheets, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- COC Withdrawal information (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Checking account records, 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Purchase receipts, 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Expenses, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Treasurer's reports, 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Guidelines and procedures for trip leaders, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Dripstone, 1964-90 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Old Correspondence, 1969-79 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Dripstone, 1962-89 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- The BPOC log, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Caver info, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Caving organization membership applications, 1984-87 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Cornell grotto annual reports, 1971-89 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Dripstone: masters and copies of masthead and section headings, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Dues schedule (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Dripstone copies, Spring 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Old returned checks, 1990-96 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Cornell Bond, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Cornell Grotto constitution, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Expense budgets, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Caving Equipment, 1956-91 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Dripstone Vol 1 Original, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Dripstone Mailing (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Dripstone, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Dripstone, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- The Dripstone, 1978-80 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Caving correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Outing Club slides, photographs, 1985-2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Caving bulletins, 1974-80 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Catskill Maps (Box 4, Folder 2)
- New York state climbing and caving, 1990's (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Airin Our Views, 1982-91 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Pennsylvania Caves, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Albany Caves, 1962-74 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Caves of the Northeast, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Caves of Massachusetts, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- COC activities and newsletter, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Donut hole trail maps (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Supplies and books (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Cave report forms (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Safety: accident report forms and rescue info, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Maps of West Virginia: road maps, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Point east: Vermont (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Newsletters, 1970-83 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Flyers (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Virginia cave maps (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Safety: accidental reports (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Cave maps: Georgia (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Indiana (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Caves (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Pennsylvania caves (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Caves Misc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- NRO Minutes (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Undated Misc. Climbing (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Reports of trips, meetings etc, 1940-50's (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Cave maps, surveys, and misc info (New York State), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- COC ancient history file, 1930-75 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- COC Documents, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- COC correspondence, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Trip reports, 1940's-50's (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Tax returns, 1967-69 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Valid vouchers candidates and Japes rent (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Appalachian Trial, 1969-70 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Maintenance receipts and Plantations receipts, 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Cornell Plantations, 1987-88 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Operations, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Gear sign out, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Receipts, 1998-99 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Receipts, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Budget requests, 1995-99 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Historical Documents, 1941-74 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Gorge cleanup, 1992-93 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Floor plan, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Procedures, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Outdoor guides, 1924-50 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Treasurers money orders, 1982-83 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Environmentalism, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Equipment forms (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Outing club members (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Iocalum newsletter, 1960-81 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- IOCA Bulletin, 1963-77 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Old receipts, 1994-97 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- COC Finances, 1998-99 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- COC Square dance, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Airin' Our Views, 1969-80's (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Airin' Our Views, 1962-85 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Secretary Notebooks, 1973-84 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Treasurer Forms, 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Purchase records, 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Bank Receipts, 2008-12 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Purchase Lists, 2010-11 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Order forms, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Travel Forms, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Funding, 2006-11 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Statements and checks, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- IOCA directory project, 1979-80 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Danby, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Financial History of COC, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Summary of Accounts, 1978-79 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Receipts and invoices, 1978-79 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Guidelines and Procedures, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Weekly attendance, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Trip records, 1997-98 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Outing Club Trip, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Intercollegiate Outing Club Association (IOCA) 1941 3rd Annual Song Fest book, 1941 (Box 6)
  Owned by Bill Sumner, Algonquin Lodge.
- Mary Alice Dietrich Scrapbook (Box 6, Folder 1)
- COC Scrapbook (Box 6, Folder 2)
- IOCR Conference, April 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Undated Photos (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Includes photos of Beebe Lake, including winter carnival
- Miscellaneous Photos, 1940s-2000s (Box 6, Folder 5-9)
  Photos some labeled and some not, include images from trips and members over several decades. Trips include camping, caving, activities on Beebe Lake, and others.